RAY. ; After I killed them, I dropped the gun in the Thames,
杀死他们之后 我把枪扔进了泰晤士河
washed the residue off me hands in the bathroom of a Burger King,
在汉堡王的卫生间洗干净手上的血 （汉堡王是美国快餐三巨头之一）
and walked home to await instructions.
然后回家等着下一次的任务
Shortly thereafter, the instructions came through.
不一会，命令来了
"Get the fuck out of London, youse dumb fucks.
“你们两个蠢货，滚出伦敦去
"Get to Bruges."
到布鲁日去”
I didn't even know where Bruges fucking was.
我他妈布鲁日在哪都不知道
It's in Belgium.
原来是在比利时
RAY. ; Bruges is a shithole.
布鲁日真是个屎坑
KEN. ; Bruges is not a shithole.
布鲁日才不是个屎坑
Bruges is a shithole.
布鲁日就是个屎坑
Ray, we've only just got off the fucking train.
雷，我们刚他妈下火车呢
Could we reserve judgment on Bruges until we've seen the fucking place?
你能等看到了布鲁日再 说它烂不烂好吧？
I know it's gonna be a shithole.
不用看我就知道那是个屎坑
(SOFTLY) Shithole.
屎坑
I think you have a couple of rooms booked under Cranham and Blakely?
我想克兰哈姆和布莱克里是在您这 订了两个房间吧？
Yes. No, we have one room booked.
是的，哦不，只订了一个房间
One twin room. Booked for two weeks.
一个双人间，订了两周
Two weeks!
两个星期？！
Do you have another room?
还有房间吗？
No, I'm afraid we're fully booked.
没有，很抱歉都被订完了
With Christmas, everywhere is fully booked.
快圣诞节了，哪都客满的
Okay.
好吧
It's very pretty.
真是美极了
I'm not being funny, we can't stay here.
跟你说吧，我们不能住在这
We've got to stay here until he rings.
我们在他来电话之前 必须得住在这
Well, what if he doesn't ring for two weeks?
喔，如果他两周都没给电话呢？
Then we stay here for two weeks.
那我们就在这呆两周
For two weeks? In fucking Bruges? In a room like this?
呆两周？在鸟不拉屎的布鲁日？ 在这样的房间里？
With you? No way!
和你？门都没有！
Ray, I really don't like to say this...
雷，我可不想说…
You really don't like to say what?
你不想说什么？
Well... You know?
喔…你知道的
Fucking bring that up.
又提那事
Do you think this is good?
你觉得这样好玩吗？
Do I think what's good?
我觉得什么好玩？
You know, going round in a boat, looking at stuff.
坐着船四处转悠，东看看西瞅瞅
Yes, I do.
当然好玩了
It's called "sightseeing."
这就是“看风景”
Oh, look at that.
哦，看那个
It's a former hospital. From the 1100s.
那以前是个医院 1100年建的
Bruges is the most well-preserved medieval town
很明显布鲁日是比利时保护的
in the whole of Belgium, apparently.
最好的中古世纪小镇了
Coming up? What's up there?
- 上去吧？ - 那里有什么好看的？
The view.
风景啊
The view of what? The view of down here? I can see that from down here.
什么的风景？俯瞰这屎坑的风景？ 我在这一样能看见
Ray, you're about the worst tourist in the whole world.
雷，你算是世界上最不 “称职”的游客了
Ken, I grew up in Dublin. I love Dublin.
肯，我是在都柏林长大的 我爱都柏林
If I'd grown up on a farm and was retarded, Bruges might impress me.
如果我是在一个农场里长大的乡巴佬 布鲁日也许会让我惊叹不已
But I didn't, so it doesn't.
但是我不是，所以我不会
Trying to get rid of me coins.
把我的硬币先用完吧
3, 3.50, 4,
3，3.5，4
4.10, 4.20, 4.30, 4.40, 4.50, 4.60,
4.1，4.2，4.3 4.4，4.5，4.6
4.70,
4.7
4.80,
4.8
4.90.
4.9
Will you take 4.90?
就4.9欧元行吗？
Entry is 5 euro.
门票是5欧元
Come on, man, it's only 10 cents.
拜托，大哥，就差10分而已
Happy in your work?
工作开心吗？
Very happy.
相当开心
I like it here.
我喜欢这
MAN: Been to the top of the tower?
去过塔顶了吗？
Yeah. Yeah, it's rubbish.
嗯，烂极了
It is? The guidebook says it's a "must-see".
是吗？旅行指南说那是“必看”呢
Well, you lot ain't going up there.
喔，你们几个可上不去
Pardon me? Why?
什么意思？为什么？
I mean, it's all windy stairs. I'm not being funny.
我是说，楼梯可承受不了太重的东西 我可不是说笑哦
What exactly are you trying to say?
你到底想说什么？
What exactly am I trying to say?
我到底想说什么？
Youse are a bunch of fucking elephants!
你们几个肥猪太胖啦！
Right, you...
你…
Come on, leave it, fatty.
来啊，死肥猪
You know, you're just the rudest man. The rudest man!
知道吗，你太无礼了！太粗鲁了！
What's all that about?
怎么了？
They're not going up there.
他们要上去
Hey, guys, I wouldn't go up there. It's really narrow.
嘿，伙计们，要是我就不上去了 楼梯小了
Screw you, motherfucker!
滚你妈逼！
Americans, isn't it?
美国人，是吧？
Now, this is more like it. Proper holidays.
现在这样才像样嘛，专属假期
One gay beer for my gay friend,
同性恋啤酒 给 同性恋朋友 （德国的施密特世家酿造）
and one normal beer for me, because I am normal.
我的普通啤酒，因为我是正常的
This is the life.
这才叫生活
We're not staying here getting pissed.
我们呆在这里可不是 为了喝的酩酊大醉
We are quietly sightseeing, like he says,
我们在这里静静的看风景，就像他说的
and awaiting his call to see what we do next.
然后等着他的电话看下一步做什么
This is my vote on what we should do.
我认为我们该这么办
We give it another day, two days, max.
我们再等一天，最多两天
Then we check the papers again, and if there's still nothing in them,
然后看有没有消息，如果还是没有
we phone him and say, "Harry, thank you for the trip to Bruges,
我们就给他电话说，“哈里，谢谢你 把我们弄到布鲁日来旅游
"it's been very nice, all the old buildings and that,
这里棒极了，古建筑啊什么的
"but we're coming back to London now, and hide out in a proper country,
不过我们现在回伦敦了 然后在乡下渡假
"where it isn't all just fucking chocolates."
那里最少不是哪都是巧克力” （比利时巧克力很出名）
My vote would be we quietly sightsee, like he says,
我觉得我们安心的看风景 就像他说的
and await his call to see what we do next.
然后等他的电话看下一步做什么
You don't even know we're here hiding out.
我们甚至不知道我们是否是来渡假的
What are you talking about?
你瞎说什么呢？
You don't even know we're not here on a job.
我们甚至不知道我们是否来干活的
What, on a job? Yeah.
- 什么，干活？ - 对
Here in Bruges?
- 在布鲁日？
Here in Bruges, on a job? Yeah.
- 在布鲁日，干活？ - 对
Why? What did he actually say?
为什么？他到底怎么说的？
He didn't actually say anything.
他其实什么也没说
Then why do you think it might be? I don't think anything.
- 那你为什么那么想？ - 我没有怎么想
But it's a bit fucking over-elaborate, isn't it?
不过还真他妈有点小题大做哈，对吧？
"Go take him to hide out." "Go take him to hide out where?"
“带他出去转转” “带他去哪？”
"Go take him to hide out in fucking Bruges."
“他妈的让他到布鲁日去”
You can hide out in Croydon.
你在克罗伊登也能渡假不是？ （英国大伦敦南侧的一个区）
Hmm.
嗯
Or Coventry.
在考文垂也行 （英国英格兰西米德兰郡城市）
It is a bit over-elaborate.
是有点小题大做了
But we haven't got any guns.
不过我们还没枪呢
Harry can get guns anywhere.
哈里在哪都能弄到枪的
He's not gonna ring tonight.
他今晚不会来电话的
Let's go out.
我们出去走走吧
Go out where? The pub.
- 去哪？ - 酒馆啊
No!
不行！
Let's go out and have a look at some of the...
我们出去看看那些
All the old medieval buildings and that.
中古世纪的建筑什么的
Because I bet they look even better at night, all lit up.
晚上所有的灯都开着 我打赌它们会更漂亮的
Yes!
成功！
That there is called the Gruuthuse Museum.
那是格吕德尤斯博物馆
They all have funny names, don't they?
它们的名字都怪怪的，是吧？
Yes, Flemish.
对，那是佛兰德斯语
In here it says, "The Belgians twice sheltered fugitive English Kings
这上面说，“比利时人在1471和1651年 两次庇佑了
"from being murdered, 1471 and 1651."
逃亡的英国国王，使他们免遭杀害”
I used to hate history, didn't you?
我讨厌历史，你呢？
It's all just a load of stuff that's already happened.
只是记录已经发生的事情的故纸堆
What are they doing over there?
他们在这干嘛呢？
They're filming something. They're filming midgets!
他们在拍什么 他们在拍侏儒呢！
Ray!
雷！
MAN: So, on this scene, you're supposed to walk like a little, tiny mouse, yeah?
那么，在这剧情里，你要像 一只小巧玲珑的老鼠一样走路，明白？
Okay? Great.
明白了？好极了
Ray, come on, let's go.
雷，好了，走吧
My arse, "Let's go." They're filming midgets.
滚开，“我们走” 他们可是在拍侏儒呢
Oh, my God! Look at that girl.
哦，天！看那个女孩
She's gorgeous!
真是正点！
Ray, we're going right now.
雷，我们马上走
Fuck off, are we!
滚开，要走自己走！
This is the best bit of Bruges so far. You and your buildings.
这是来到布鲁日以来让我最开心的事情了 你是喜欢看建筑哈
Hello.
好啊
Do you speak English? No.
- 你会说英语吗？ - 不会
Yes, you do. Everybody does.
不，你会，谁都会的
What are you filming midgets for?
你们拍侏儒干什么啊？
It's a Dutch movie. It's a dream sequence.
是一部荷兰电影，其中的一段梦境
It's a pastiche of Nicholas Roeg's Don't Look Now.
模仿尼古拉斯·罗格的《威尼斯疑魂》
Not a pastiche, but a...
不是模仿，拍这电影是为了…
A"homage" is too strong. A"nod of the head"?
说“表示敬意”可能太过了 那说“表示赞同”吧？
Wow, your English is very good.
哇噢，你的英语很好嘛
A lot of midgets tend to kill themselves.
很多侏儒都试图自杀
A disproportionate amount.
人数多的难以想象
Herve Villechaize, off of Fantasy Island.
演《梦幻岛》的赫维·维利伽兹
I think somebody off The Time Bandits.
还是《时光大盗》？
I suppose they must get really sad about, like,
我猜他们一定因为太矮小什么的
being really little and that.
而非常难过
People looking at them and laughing at them.
大家看着他们，取笑他们
Calling them names. You know, "shortarse."
骂他们，你知道，“死矮子”什么的
There's another famous midget I'm missing, but I can't remember.
我还记得一个著名的侏儒 不过名字我忘记了
It's not the R2-D2 man. No, he's still going.
不是说R2-D2（星球大战里的小机器人） 不，他在电影里还活着呢
I hope your midget doesn't kill himself. Your dream sequence will be fucked.
我希望你那位侏儒不会寻短见 要不梦境你就拍不了了
He doesn't like being called a midget. He prefers "dwarf."
他不喜欢被人叫做侏儒 他喜欢“小矮人”
Well, this is exactly my point!
喔，这就是我想说的
People go around calling you a midget when you want to be called a dwarf.
大家都叫你侏儒 不过你却想被人称作“小矮人”
Of course you're gonna blow your head off!
当然你会抓狂了
My name's Ray. What's yours? Chloe.
- 我叫雷，你呢？ - 克洛伊
How did you get past the security man?
你是怎么躲过保安的？
Getting past security men, it's sort of my job.
躲过保安可是我的工作
You're a shoplifter?
你是小偷？
(CHUCKLES) No, not a shoplifter.
不，才不是呢
It's a good joke, though.
不过你还真幽默
No.
不过我不是
I'll tell you what I am at dinner tomorrow night.
明天一起晚餐的时候 我就告诉你我是干嘛的
Fuck.
完了
How fucking cool.
操!帅!
Mr. Blakely?
布莱克里先生？
Yes. No, Mr. Cranham. No. Yes. Mr. Blakely. Yes.
是我，不，我是克兰哈姆先生 不，是，布莱克里先生，是的
You have a message.
你有留言
Shit!
靠！
HARRY. ; Number one, why aren't you in when I fucking told you to be in?
第一，他妈的让你呆着你非得出去？
Number two, why doesn't this hotel have phones with fucking voicemail
第二，他妈的旅店的电话 连语音信箱都没有
and not I have to leave messages with the fucking receptionist?
我他妈的还得通过他妈接待员留言？
Number three, you better fucking be in tomorrow night when I fucking call again
第三，你他妈的最好明晚 在我来电话的时候他妈呆在旅店里
or there'll be fucking Hell to pay, I'm fucking telling you. Harry.
不然他妈有你好看 到时别他妈怪我没和你说
Would you turn the fucking light off!
他妈的关灯！
Sorry, Ken.
抱歉，肯
Keep the fucking noise down!
他妈小声点
Someone's in a mood.
有人心情不好啊
(SOFTLY) You'll never guess what.
你猜猜看刚才发生了什么
Will you shut your fucking mouth, please, and go to sleep?
能请您老把嘴闭上 然后他妈的赶紧上床睡觉吗？
Oh, sorry.
哦，抱歉
Except I've gotta take me contact lenses out.
不过我得先把隐形眼镜拿出来
Altogether,
总的
I had
我喝了
five pints of beer and six bottles.
五品脱又六瓶啤酒
No. Six pints of beer and seven bottles.
不，六品脱又七瓶
And you know what? I'm not even pissed!
相信吗？我尿都没撒一次！
You'll never guess what, Ken.
你绝对猜不到刚才发生了什么，肯
Ken, you'll never guess what. What?
- 你绝对猜不到刚才发生了什么，肯 - 什么？
Got a date for tomorrow night.
我明晚有约会啦
I'm very happy for you.
真替你感到高兴
With a girl.
和一个女孩子呢
Can you turn the light off, please?
能劳驾您老把灯关了吗？
Only been in Bruges one day, got a date with a girl in the film business,
在布鲁日呆了一天，就和一个女孩约会了 她是电影行业的哦
the Belgian film business.
比利时电影业的
They're doing a film about a midget.
他们在拍关于侏儒的电影
Miss?
小姐？
Marie?
玛丽小姐？
Sorry about the message last night. The man who left it is a bit of a...
昨晚的留言很抱歉了 留言的那人有点…
Well, he's a bit of a...
喔，他有点…
Cock?
贱？
Yes. He's a bit of a cock.
对，他有点贱
Morning.
早安
Harry called last night.
哈里昨晚来电话了
We missed him.
我们没接到
Jeez, he swears a lot, doesn't he?
天，他一定“他妈的”很多次，是吧？
We're staying in tonight. Whatever happens.
无论如何今晚我们得呆在旅馆了
Hmm.
嗯
Except...
除了…
Except "hmm" what?
除了“嗯”什么？
Except only one of us needs to stay in, really.
除了我们只需要一个人留下就行了，真的
Uh-huh.
嗯哼
And which one of us would that be, now, Ray?
那是谁留下呢，雷？
I thought you didn't like Bruges.
我感觉你不喜欢布鲁日啊
I don't like Bruges, it's a shithole.
我不喜欢布鲁日，这个屎坑
But I did already say I had a date with a Belgian lady
不过我已经说了我和比利时电影业
in the Belgian film business, which I did already say about before.
一个女孩子有约会了
Just don't get into any fucking trouble.
别惹他妈麻烦啊
We're keeping a low profile.
我们得低调
And this morning, and this afternoon,
还有，今天上午，今天下午
we are doing what I want to do.
我们做我想做的事情
Got it? Of course.
- 明白了？ - 知道了
Which, I presume, will involve culture.
我想，肯定是和文明什么的啊有关了
Oh, we shall strike a balance between culture and fun.
哦，我们平衡一下文明和乐趣的
Somehow I believe, Ken, that the balance shall tip in the favor of culture.
不过我相信，肯，平衡会向文明倾斜的
Like a big, fat, fucking retarded, fucking black girl
就像跷跷板的一边 他妈的是一个粗壮的黑人女孩
on a seesaw, opposite
对面呢
a dwarf.
是一个小矮子
(SOFTLY) Ray, did we or did we not agree
雷，我们是不是达成协议说
that if I let you go on your date tonight,
如果今晚我让你去约会
we'd do the things I wanted to do today?
那白天就做我想做的事？
We are doing the things that you wanted to do today.
我们现在正在做你想做的事啊
And that we'd do them without you throwing a fucking moody,
那你现在他妈的乱发脾气
like some 5-year-old who's dropped all his sweets?
像个5岁的孩子丢了自己的糖果似的？
I didn't agree to that.
这我可没答应
I'll cheer up.
好吧，我会提起精神的
Up there, the top altar, is a phial
在那，最上面的圣坛，是一个药瓶
brought back by a Flemish knight from the Crusades in the Holy Land.
那是一个佛兰德斯骑士在 十字军东征之时从圣地带回来的
And that phial, do you know what it's said to contain?
那个药瓶 你知道他们说里面装着什么吗？
No, what's it said to contain?
不知道，装着什么？
It's said to contain some drops of Jesus Christ's blood.
据说它装着耶稣基督的几滴血
Yeah, that's how this church got its name. Basilica of the Holy Blood.
嗯，这也是这教堂名字的由来 圣血教堂
Yeah. Yeah.
哦，哦
And this blood, right, though it's dried blood,
这血，对，尽管在千年来
at different times over many years, they say it turned back into liquid.
早已风干，不过他们说 每次风干之后，它又会变成液体
Turned back into liquid from dried blood.
从风干的血重新变成液体的血
At various times of great
如此往复，不管外界
stress.
有多大的压力
Yeah? Yeah.
- 是吗？ - 是啊
So, yeah, I'm gonna go up in the queue and touch it, which is what you do.
那么，嗯，我排队上去摸摸它 你也去吧
Yeah? Yeah. You coming?
- 真的？ - 当然，你去吗？
Do I have to?
我一定得去吗？
Do you have to? Of course you don't have to.
你一定得去吗？当然你不一定得去了
It's Jesus' fucking blood, isn't it? Of course you don't fucking have to!
那是我操耶稣的血呢，对吧？ 我操你当然可以不用去了！
Of course you don't fucking have to!
你他妈的当然可以不用去了！
You little fucking cunt.
他妈你个小笨蛋
RAY. ; Murder, Father.
杀人，神父
PRIEST. ; Why did you murder someone, Raymond?
你为何杀人，雷蒙？
For money, Father.
为了钱，神父
For money?
为了钱？
You murdered someone for money?
你杀人就为了钱？
Yes, Father.
是的，神父
Not out of anger, not out of nothing. For money.
不是出于愤怒，不是因为其他的任何原因 只是为了钱
Who did you murder for money, Raymond?
你为了钱杀了谁，雷蒙？
You, Father.
您，神父
I'm sorry?
什么？
I said you, Father. What, are you deaf?
我说您，神父，怎么，您耳背吗？
Harry Waters says hello.
哈里·沃特斯向您问安
The little boy.
无辜的孩子
RAY: I quite like this one.
我喜欢这个
All the rest were rubbish by spastics, but this one's quite good.
其他的都是垃圾，不过这幅棒极了
What's that all about, then?
这说的是什么呢？
It's Judgment Day, you know? Oh, yeah.
- 最后审判日，知道吧？ - 哦，知道
What's that then?
那又是什么？
Well, it's, you know, the final day on Earth.
喔，那是，你知道 世界末日
When mankind will be judged for all the crimes they've committed and that.
那时人类将承担起他们所犯的罪孽
And see who gets into Heaven and who gets into Hell and all that?
看谁能进入天堂，谁得坠入地狱？
Yeah.
对
And what's the other place?
还有什么？
Purgatory.
炼狱
Purgatory?
炼狱？
Purgatory's kind of like the in-betweeny one.
炼狱是类似于中间物的地方
You weren't really shit, but you weren't all that great, either.
你不算太坏，但也称不上好
Like Tottenham.
和托特纳姆一样 （伦敦北部最阴暗城市）
Do you believe in all that stuff, Ken?
你相信那些吗，肯？
About Tottenham?
托特纳姆？
The Last Judgment and the afterlife.
最后审判日和来生
Guilt and sins and
罪恶，犯罪
Hell and all that?
地狱啊，等等？
Um...
呃…
Well...
喔…
KEN: I don't know, Ray. I don't know what I believe.
我不知道，雷 我也不知道我相信什么
The things you're taught as a child, they never really leave you, do they?
你小时候学到的东西 永远都会伴随着你，是吧？
So, like, I believe in trying to lead a good life.
比如，我想好好过日子
Like, if there's an old lady, carrying her shopping home,
如果有个老奶奶，要把买的东西弄回家
I don't try and help her carry her shopping, I don't go that far,
我不会试着帮她扛东西 我没有那么高尚
but I'll certainly hold the door open for her and that, and let her go out before me.
但是我会为她把门打开 让她先出去
Yeah. And anyway, if you tried to help her carry her shopping,
嗯，不管怎么样 如果你想帮她扛东西
she'd probably think you were just trying to nick her shopping.
她也许会想你是想偷她的东西呢
Exactly. This is the world we live in today.
- 的确 - 这个世界就是这个样子
At the same time as trying to lead a good life,
在想好好生活的同时
I have to reconcile myself with the fact that, yes, I have killed people.
我也得不断的对我杀过人 自我麻醉，自我安慰
Not many people. Most of them were not very nice people.
不是很多，他们大部分都不算是好人
Apart from one person.
除了一个
Who's that?
谁？
This fellow, Danny Aliband's brother.
丹尼·艾里班的兄弟
He was just trying to protect his brother. Like you or I would.
他只是想保护他的兄弟而已 就像你和我都会做的一样
He was just a lollipop man.
他只是个护送员 （在学校门口护送小学生过马路的人）
He came at me with a bottle. What are you gonna do?
他拿着个瓶子朝着我过来 你还能怎么办？
I shot him down.
我对着他开了枪
Hmm.
嗯
In my book, though, sorry, someone comes at you with a bottle,
不过在我看来，抱歉，如果有人 拿着瓶子想打你
that is a deadly weapon, he's gotta take the consequences.
那可是致命的武器 所以他得承受后果
I know that in my heart.
我心里清楚得很
I also know that he was just trying to protect his brother, you know?
我还知道他只是 想保护他的兄弟，知道吗？
I know. But a bottle, that can kill you.
我知道，但是一个瓶子，那能把你杀死的
It's a case of it's you or him.
不是你死就是他死
If he'd come at you with his bare hands, that'd be different.
如果他空手朝你杀过来 那就是两码事了
That wouldn't have been fair.
那就不公平了
Well, technically, your bare hands can kill somebody, too.
喔，从技术角度来讲 你赤手空拳也能杀死人啊
They can be deadly weapons, too. I mean, what if he knew karate, say?
它们也能算是凶器呢 我是说，比如，万一他会空手道呢？
You said he was a lollipop man.
你都说他是个护送员
He was a lollipop man.
他是个护送员
What's a lollipop man doing knowing fucking karate?
一个护送员他妈的干嘛要会空手道？
I'm just saying.
我只是说说而已
How old was he? About 50.
- 他多大了？ - 50左右
What's a 50-year-old lollipop man doing knowing fucking karate?
一个50岁的护送员 他妈的干嘛要会空手道？
What was he, a Chinese lollipop man?
他是谁，一个中国护送员？
Jesus, Ken, I'm trying to talk about...
天哪，肯，我是想说…
I know what you're trying to talk about.
我知道你要说什么
I killed a little boy. You keep bringing up fucking lollipop men!
我杀了一个小孩子 你他妈的干嘛不停的提什么护送员！
You didn't mean to kill a little boy.
你不是故意杀死那个小孩子的啊
I know I didn't mean to.
我知道我不是有意的
But because of the choices I made and the course that I put into action,
但是因为我的选择和我的所作所为
a little boy isn't here anymore.
一个小孩永远的去了
And he'll never be here again.
他再也不会回来这了
I mean here in the world, not here in Belgium.
我说“这”指的是这个世界 不是说这里
Well, he'll never be here in Belgium, either, will he?
喔，他也不能来这里了，对吧？
I mean, he might have wanted to come here when he got older.
我是说，也许他长大了会想来这里呢
I don't know why.
我不知道为什么
And that's all because of me.
那都是因为我
He's dead because of me.
因为我他死了
And I'm trying to...
我试着…
I'm trying to get me head around it, but I can't.
我试着忘记，可我不能
I will always have killed that little boy.
就是我杀死了那个小孩子
That ain't ever going away. Ever.
这永远都不会改变，永远不会
Unless...
除非…
Maybe I go away.
除非我也死去
Don't even think like that.
别乱想了
You look good.
你看起来很帅了
What's it matter anyway?
有什么关系呢？
So, what do you do, Raymond?
你是干嘛的，雷蒙？
I shoot people for money.
我杀人赚钱
What kinds of people?
杀什么样的人呢？
Priests. Children. You know, the usual.
神父，孩子，你知道，平常人
Is there a lot of money to be made in that line of business?
这行当很赚钱吗？
There is in priests. There isn't in children.
杀神父有钱赚 杀小孩就没有了
So what is it you do, Chloe?
那你是干什么的，克洛伊？
I sell cocaine and heroin to Belgian film crews.
我卖可卡因和海洛因给 比利时电影工作人员
Do you?
是吗？
Do I look like I do?
我看起来像吗？
You do, actually.
嗯，挺像的
Do I look like I shoot people?
我看起来像会杀人吗？
No.
不会杀人
Just children.
只杀孩子吧
Mmm-hmm.
嗯哼
I saw your midget today. Little prick didn't even say hello.
我今天看见了你的侏儒 他居然招呼都不打
Well, he's on a lot of ketamine.
喔，他用的克他命太多了吧 (一种高效麻醉剂)
What's that?
那是什么？
Horse tranquilizer.
合成海洛英
A horse tranquilizer?
合成海洛英？
Where'd he get that? I sold it to him.
- 他从哪弄到的？ - 我卖给他的
You can't sell horse tranquilizers to a midget!
你怎么能把合成海洛英卖给一个侏儒！
This movie, I think it's gonna be a very good one.
这电影，我想它会很成功的
There's never been a classic movie made in Bruges until now.
到现在在布鲁日 还没有拍出一部经典电影呢
Of course there hasn't, it's a shithole.
当然没有了，这个屎坑
Bruges is my hometown, Ray.
布鲁日是我家乡，雷
Well, it's still a shithole.
喔，它还是个屎坑
It's not a shithole.
才不是呢
What? Even midgets have to take drugs to stick it.
是吗？连侏儒都得嗑药才能顶住
Okay.
好吧
So, you've insulted my hometown.
你侮辱了我的家乡
You're doing very well, Raymond.
你做的很成功，雷蒙
Why don't you tell me some Belgian jokes while you're at it?
给我讲几个关于比利时的笑话吧？
I don't know any Belgian jokes.
我不知道哦
And if I did, I think I'd have the good sense not to...
如果我知道的话 我就不会…
Hey, hang on. Is Belgium where there were all those child abuse murders lately?
嘿，等等，比利时最近是不是很多 虐待孩子的凶手？
Then I do know a Belgian joke.
那我就知道一个笑话了
What's Belgium famous for?
比利时什么出名啊？
Chocolates and child abuse.
巧克力和虐待儿童
And they only invented the chocolates to get to the kids.
他们发明那些巧克力 就是为了吸引那些孩子
What?
什么？
One of the girls they murdered was a friend of mine.
他们杀死的其中一个 女孩是我的好朋友
I'm sorry, Chloe.
很抱歉，克洛伊
One of the girls they murdered wasn't a friend of mine.
他们杀死的其中一个 女孩不是我的好朋友
I just wanted to make you feel bad.
我只是想让你郁闷罢了
And it worked. Quite well.
还真有效，好极了
Fucking unbelievable.
真他妈没教养
What's fucking unbelievable?
有什么他妈的没教养的？
Are you talking to me?
你是在和我说话？
(SOFTLY) He pauses, even though he should just hit the cunt.
他停顿了一下，尽管他只需要 打那个混蛋一顿
And he repeats.
他重复了一遍
Yes, I am talking to you. What's fucking unbelievable?
是的，我是和你说话 有什么他妈的没教养的？
Well, I'll tell you what's fucking unbelievable, shall I?
喔，我告诉你他妈的有什么没教养的 好吧？
Blowing cigarette smoke straight into myself and my girlfriend's face.
把烟直接喷在我和我女朋友的脸上
That's fucking unbelievable!
就这个他妈的没教养！
This is the smoking section. I don't care if it's the smoking section.
- 这是吸烟区 - 我他妈不管
All right? She directed it right in my face, man.
好吧？她直接把烟他妈吐我脸上，伙计
I don't wanna die just because of your fucking arrogance. Uh-huh.
我可不想因为你他妈无知而早逝
Isn't that what the Vietnamese used to say?
越南人以前也就是这么说的吧？
Vietnamese? What are you talking about, the Vietnamese?
越南人？你他妈说什么呢？越南人？
That statement makes no fucking sense at all.
一点他妈关系都没有
Yes it does. The Vietnamese!
怎么没关系，越南人！
Well, saying it over and over ain't gonna make any more sense out of it.
喔，一遍接一遍的说 你还是在胡说八道
How does the Vietnamese have any relevance whatsoever
越南人和我以及我女朋友
to myself and my girlfriend having to breathe
得吸你女朋友的二手烟
your friend's cigarette smoke?
有个什么狗屁联系？
Tell me how saying...
你告诉我…
That's for John Lennon, you Yankee fucking cunt!
这是替约翰·列侬打的！你个美国佬！ （列侬，披头士成员，被美国人枪杀）
A bottle? No, don't bother.
瓶子？别费劲了
We're leaving.
我们走
I don't hit women! I would never hit a woman, Chloe!
我不打女人！ 我从来不打女人，克洛伊！
I'd hit a woman who was trying to hit me with a bottle!
我打女人是因为她拿着个瓶子想砸我！
That's different. That's self-defense, isn't it?
这就不同了，这是自卫，对吧？
Or a woman who could do karate.
要是她会空手道呢？
I'd never hit a woman generally, Chloe. Don't think that.
我从来不会打普通女人的，克洛伊 别乱想了
God, you're pretty.
神哪，你真美
I have to make a call.
我得打个电话
Oh, no.
哦，别那样
You've gone off me, now, haven't you? Just because I hit that fucking cow.
你要离开我了，是吧？ 就因为我打了那个臭女人
Hello? HARRY. ; Where the fuck were you yesterday?
- 你好 - 你他妈昨天跑哪去了？
We just popped out for some dinner, Harry. We only popped out for half an hour.
我们出去吃晚餐了，就出去了半个小时
Yeah? What'd you have?
是吗？吃什么了？
For dinner? Yeah.
- 晚餐吃什么了？ - 嗯
Pizza, at Pizza Hut.
披萨，在必胜客吃的
Was it nice?
好吃吧？
Yeah, it was all right. I don't know. It was Pizza Hut.
嗯，很不错 我也不清楚，是必胜客嘛
The same as in England.
和英国的一样
Well, that's globalization, isn't it? Is Ray there with you?
喔，这就是全球化啊，对吧？ 雷和你在一块吗？
He's in the toilet.
他在卫生间里
Can he hear? No.
- 他能听见吗？ - 不能
What's he doing?
他在干什么？
What do you mean? Is he doing a wee or a poo?
- 什么意思 - 他是小便还是大便？
I don't know, Harry, the door's closed.
我不知道，哈里，门关了
Send him out on an errand for half an hour, but don't make it sound suspicious.
让他出去半个小时干点什么 不过别让他起疑心
Ray? Why don't you go out down to the pub for half an hour?
雷？你想到酒馆待个半个小时吗？
Yeah, yeah, I know I said you couldn't,
嗯嗯，我知道我说过你不能出去
but might as well enjoy ourselves, eh?
不过还是得放松一下，是吧？
No, I don't know if they've got bowling anywhere. Could have a look.
不，我不知道有没有保龄球馆 你可以去看看
Yeah, see you.
好，回见
Yeah. He's gone.
好了，他走了
What'd you say to him?
你和他怎么说？
I said, " Why don't you go have a drink, you say you've been cooped up?"
我说，“你出去喝一杯吧 你不是说这像坐牢吗？”
What did he say? Said, yeah, he would.
- 他怎么说？ - 他说，好的，他去
And he might go have a look to see if there's a bowling alley around.
他想看看能不能打保龄球
Was he just having a wee?
他刚才是在小便了？
Yeah, I think so. I assume so.
嗯，我想是吧，我猜是的
Sure he didn't mind?
确定他没起疑？
No, he was glad to get out.
没有，他很高兴能出去
He's definitely gone?
他真的走了？
Yeah, yeah, he slammed the door.
嗯，一甩门出去了
That don't mean he's gone. Go check outside the door.
那不代表他走了 去门外看看
Harry, he's definitely gone.
哈里，他的确走了
You realize there are no bowling alleys in Bruges?
你知道布鲁日没有保龄球场吗？
I realize that, Harry. The boy wanted to have a look anyway.
我知道，哈里，他还是想去找找看
What are they gonna have, a medieval fucking bowling alley?
他们会有什么，一个他妈的 中古世纪的保龄球场？
As I say, I think he was just glad to get out and about.
我说了，他就是想出去走走
So, is he having a nice time, seeing all the canals and that?
那，他开心吗，看那些运河什么的？
I had a lovely time when I was there.
我去那的时候开心极了
All the canals and the old buildings and that.
那些运河啊，古老建筑啊什么的
When were you here?
你什么时候来的？
When I was seven. Last happy holiday I fucking had.
我七岁的时候 他妈的我的最后一个快乐的假期
Have you been on a canal trip, yet? Yeah.
- 坐着船在运河上逛了吗？ - 嗯
Have you been down, like, all the old cobbled streets and that?
在那些古老的大卵石街道上走过了吧？
Yeah.
嗯
It's like a fairytale, isn't it, that place? Yeah.
- 那里就像是童话般美丽，是吧？ - 对
With the churches and that. They're Gothic. Yeah.
- 那些教堂，是中古世纪的吧
Is it Gothic?
- 是中古世纪的吧？ - 对
So he's having a really nice time?
那他过得很开心了？
Well, I'm having a really nice time.
喔，我在这里过得很开心
I'm not sure if it's really his cup of tea.
我不知道他是否喜欢了
What?
什么？
You know, I'm not sure if it's really his thing.
你知道，我不知道他是不是喜欢
What do you mean, "It's not really his thing"?
你说“他不太喜欢”是什么意思？
What's that supposed to mean,
“他不太喜欢”是什么意思？
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
那他妈的是什么意思？
Nothing, Harry.
没什么，哈里
It's a fairytale fucking town, isn't it?
那里他妈的是童话般的地方，是吧？
How can a fairytale town not be somebody's fucking thing?
一个童话般的小镇他妈的怎么可能 有人不喜欢？
How can all those canals and bridges and cobbled streets and those churches,
那些运河，石桥，石街，教堂
all that beautiful fucking fairytale stuff,
都他妈是童话里的东西
how can that not be somebody's fucking thing, eh?
怎么可能有人他妈不喜欢，嗯？
What I think I meant to say was...
我想我的意思是…
Is the swan still there? Yeah, the swan's...
- 那天鹅还在那吗？ - 在，那天鹅…
How can fucking swans not fucking be somebody's fucking thing, eh?
他妈的天鹅怎么可能有人他妈的不喜欢？
How can that be?
那怎么可能？
What I think I meant to say was,
我想我的意思是
when he first arrived, he wasn't quite sure about it.
刚到的时候 他不是很喜欢
You know, there's that big, dual carriageway when you get off the train?
你知道，刚下车你就能看见 一个大的，双轨车道吧？
It mightn't have been here when you were here last, Harry.
哈里，可能你最后来的那次 那东西还没有呢
Well, as soon as he got into, like, the old town proper,
喔，当他进入这个古老的小镇之后
and he saw the canals and the bridges and, you know, the swans and that,
他看见那些运河，那些石桥 那些天鹅啊什么的
well, he just fucking loved it then.
他他妈的就喜欢上了
Couldn't get enough of it, the medieval part of town.
怎么都看不够，那些中古世纪的东西
It was just that initial, dual carriageway thing sort of put him off for a second.
只是在开始，那些双轨车道让他有点不爽
Don't know if I remember a dual carriageway.
我不记得有没有双轨车道了
Must be recent.
一定最近才有的
Hasn't spoilt it, has it?
没把那毁了吧，啊？
No, no, no, it's just that initial thing.
没有没有 只是一开始感觉不好而已
And you know what?
你知道吗？
As we were walking through the streets,
当我们走在大街上
there was this sort of freezing fog hanging over everything,
一切都是雾蒙蒙的
and it made it look almost like a fairytale or something.
看起来就像是仙境一般
And he turned to me, do you know what he said?
他转过头对我说 你知道他说了什么吗？
What'd he say?
他说什么？
He said, " Ken, I know I'm awake, but I feel like I'm in a dream."
他说，“肯，我知道我醒着 不过我感觉我是在做梦一样。”
Yeah? He said that?
是吗？他那么说的？
Yeah.
嗯
Meaning, like, in a good dream?
是说，在一个美梦里？
Yeah. Of course, like in a good dream.
嗯，当然，像是在做美梦
Oh, good. I'm glad he likes it there.
哦，好极了，我很高兴他喜欢那里
I'm glad we were able to give him something.
我很高兴我们为他做点什么
Something good and happy. Because he wasn't a bad kid, was he?
做让他高兴的事 因为他不是个坏孩子，是吧？
Huh?
哈？
He wasn't a bad kid, was he?
他不是个坏孩子，是吧？
Listen, take down this address. Raamstraat 17.
听着，记下这个地址 拉姆斯查特17号
That's "Raam," like "Ram," but with an extra "a."
是“Raam”，发音和“Ram”一样 不过多了一个“a”
Raamstraat 17.
拉姆斯查特17号
You got that?
记下了？
Yes, Raamstraat 17.
嗯，拉姆斯查特17号
Good. There'll be a man there tomorrow morning at 9.;00, his name's Yuri.
很好，明早9点会有人的 他叫宥利
Yuri. He'll give you the gun.
- 宥利 - 他会给你枪的
Ring me on the public phone at Jimmy Driscoll's
事情办完了之后，用公用电话
about 3.;00 or 4.;00 tomorrow, after it's done.
在下午3点或者4点给 吉米·汉克斯家打电话找我
After what's done?
什么事情办完了之后？
Are you being thick?
你傻了？
No. Listen, I like Ray.
- 我很好啊 - 听着，我喜欢雷
He was a good bloke, but when it all comes down to it, you know,
他是个好小伙，不过直到那事发生之后
he blew the head off a little fucking kid. And you brought him in, Ken.
你知道，他妈把一个小孩杀了 他就得接受惩罚，肯
So if the buck don't stop with him, where does it stop?
如果他不负责，谁来负责？
Ken?
肯？
It stops with me, Harry. That's an easy one.
我来负责，哈里 这很简单
Look, don't get shirty, Ken.
听着，别发火，肯
Listen, I'm just glad that I was able to do something for the boy before he went.
听着，我很高兴我能在孩子走之前 为孩子做点什么
Do what for the boy?
为他做什么？
You know, have him get to see Bruges.
你知道，让他来看看布鲁日
I'd like to go to see Bruges again before I die.
我也希望死之前能再去看看布鲁日
What was it he said again about... Yeah, "It's like a dream."
他是怎么说的来着…对了 “这就像是在做梦”
"I know I'm awake, but I feel like I'm in a dream."
“我知道我醒着 可是我感觉我是在做梦”
Yeah.
嗯
Give me a call when he's dead.
他死了之后给我打个电话
That's my fucking girlfriend, you asshole.
我操那是我女朋友，你个混蛋
Eirik, what are you doing?
埃里克，你干什么呢？
Where are you from, fucker?
你是哪冒出来的，混蛋？
Ireland, originally.
爱尔兰，祖籍
And you think it's okay to come over to Belgium
你觉得跑到比利时
and fuck another man's girl?
操别人的女人心安理得是吗？
Look, I didn't know she had a boyfriend, all right?
听着，我不知道她有男朋友，好吧？
And I haven't fucked her, anyway. Ask her. I'd only put me hand on it.
我也没有操她，不信，问她 我只是摸了摸她而已
Eirik, put the gun down!
埃里克，把枪放下
Get down on your knees and open your mouth.
跪下，把嘴张开
Don't start being silly.
别傻了
Get down on your...
跪…
Exactly at what point was it that all skinheads suddenly became poofs?
什么时候光头开始变得婆婆妈妈了？
Used to be, you were a skinhead,
你是小光头的时候
you just went around beating up Pakistani 12-year-olds.
是不是只四处欺负 12岁大的巴基斯坦孩子
Now it seems a prerequisite to be a fucking bum-boy!
这就是你现在为什么 是个傻逼瘪三的主要原因吧？
That's not gonna help you, man.
那可帮不了你什么忙，伙计
Ray, there's only blanks in that gun.
雷，那是空弹
Eirik, don't!
埃里克，别！
Now who's the fucking bum-boy?
现在谁是瘪三？
You, you fucking bum-boy!
你，你个瘪三！
Chloe, what exactly is going on here?
克洛伊，这到底是怎么回事？
I can't see!
我看不见了！我看不见了！
Of course you can't fucking see! I just shot a blank in your fucking eyes!
你他妈的当然看不见了！ 我刚刚对着你的眼睛开了空枪！
Is this fella your boyfriend? No. I mean, he used to be.
- 这家伙是你男朋友吗？ - 不是，我是说，他曾经是
Well, what's he doing here?
喔，那他来这干什么？
We... We rob tourists, sometimes.
我们…我们抢劫游客，有时候
I fucking knew it was too good to be true!
他妈的我就知道天下没这么好的事！
I knew you'd have never shagged me, normally.
我就知道正常情况下 你才不可能和我上床呢！
No! That's not true, I...
不！那是真的，我…
I called it off tonight. I told him not to come tonight.
我说了今晚不行动了 我让他今晚别过来了
Why did you come tonight?
你今晚干嘛过来？
EIRIK: Chloe, I can't see, I swear it!
克洛伊，我看不见，真的！
Stop whingeing like a big gay baby.
别像个娘们似的呼天抢地的
I haven't had a shag in months!
我好几个月没和人上过床了！
I can't see out of this eye, Chloe! I have to go to the hospital!
我这个眼睛看不见了，克洛伊！ 我得去医院！
I'll drive you.
我开车送你
Great! Now the whole night's ruined!
好极了！整个晚上都毁了！
No!
不！
You can stay if you want. I just don't know how long I'll be.
你可以待在这 不过我不知道我什么时候能回来
I just knew someone like you would never like someone like me.
我就知道你这样的人 是不可能喜欢上我这样的人的
I just knew. What do you mean, someone like me?
- 我就知道 - 你说像我这样的人，是什么意思？
You know, someone nice.
你知道，好人
Call me. Please.
给我电话，一定哦
EIRIK: Chloe!
克洛伊
Cha-ching!
赚了！
Have you got some sort of problem?
你有什么病是吗？
No, no problem.
不，没有
Four beers in 20 minutes. No problem.
20分钟要了四杯啤酒 没问题
Fuck off.
去你妈的
JIMMY: Beer and a red wine.
来杯啤酒和红酒
I'll be back.
我一会就回来
How's the movie going?
电影拍的怎么样了？
It's a jumped-up Eurotrash piece of rip-off fucking bullshit.
纯粹他妈的一部自以为是 东施效颦模仿欧洲风格的垃圾
Like, in a bad way?
不好？
Your girlfriend's very pretty.
你女朋友相当漂亮啊
She ain't my girlfriend. She's a prostitute I just picked up.
她不是我女朋友 她只是我刚找来的妓女
Didn't know there were any prostitutes in Bruges.
我不知道布鲁日还有妓女
You just have to look in the right places.
你得找对地方才行
Brothels are good.
妓院里就很多
Well, you've picked up a very pretty prostitute.
喔，那你找到了一个很好的妓女
Thank you.
谢谢
You from the States?
你是美国来的？
Yeah.
嗯
But don't hold it against me.
不过别因此对我有偏见哈
I'll try not to.
尽量吧
Just try not to say anything too loud or crass.
说话别太大声或者太粗鲁就行了
Hey-ho. Drowning your sorrows, huh?
嘿，借酒浇愁呢？
What sorrows? You know, being a sad, old, ugly little man.
- 什么愁？ - 看，你是个伤心，苍老而丑陋的小矮人
One gay beer, please.
来杯Gay啤
How'd your date go?
你的约会怎么样？
My date involved two instances of extreme violence.
我的约会分成两个极其暴力的部分
One instance of her hand on my cock and my finger up her thing,
一部分是她的手放在我的鸡鸡上 我的手指在她的上面
which lasted all too briefly. Isn't that always the way?
不过春宵恨短，是不是都是这样呢？
One instance of me stealing five grams of her very-high-quality cocaine,
另外一部分 是我偷走了她五克高质量的可卡因
and one instance of me blinding a poofy little skinhead.
还有我把一个光头娘娘腔整瞎了
So, all in all, my evening pretty much balanced out fine.
所以，总的来说，今晚还是挺好的
You got five grams of coke?
你有五克可卡因？
I've got four grams on me and one gram in me,
只剩四克——那一克我已经享用完了
which is why me heart is going like the clappers,
这就是我的心脏快的像拍板一样
as if I'm about to have a heart attack.
好似要心脏病发了
So if I collapse any minute now, please remember to tell the doctors
所以如果我倒下了，记得告诉医生
that it might have something to do with the coke.
很可能和可卡因有关系
Give us a gram, then.
给我们一克吧
I thought you were laying off, because it makes you depressed?
我以为你不吸了呢，因为那会 让你感觉很沮丧？
You know what? Right now, I don't really give a fuck.
知道吗？现在我才不鸟
Why didn't you wave hello to me today when I waved hello to you today?
今天我和你挥手你怎么不理我啊？
I was on a very strong horse tranquilizer today.
我今天嗑了太多合成海洛英
I wasn't waving hello to anybody, except maybe to a horse.
我和谁都没打招呼，除了药
Huh? What are you talking about?
呃？你说什么呢？
Just horseshit.
没什么
You from America?
你是美国来的？
Yeah. But don't hold it against me.
嗯，不过不要因此看低我
Well, that's for me to decide, isn't it?
喔，这是我的事，对吧？
Are you from America, too?
你也是美国来的吗？
No, I'm from Amsterdam.
不是，我是阿姆斯特丹来的
(SCOFFS) Amsterdam.
阿姆斯特丹
Amsterdam is just a load of bloody prostitutes, isn't it?
阿姆斯特丹那都是妓女是吗？
Yes. That's why I came to Bruges.
是的，这就是我来布鲁日的原因
I thought I'd get a better price for my pussy here.
在这里我也许能把逼卖个好价钱
Huh?
哈？
You two are weird.
你们两个真怪
Would you like some cocaine?
想来点可卡因吗？
I've also got some acid and some ecstasy.
我还有迷幻药和快乐丸
Herve Villechaize, I know, did.
赫维·维利伽兹，我知道，真的
The dwarf off, I think, The Time Bandits, did.
是，我想想，《时光大盗》里的小矮子
Lots of midgets...
很多矮人…
Dwarves, top themselves.
矮子们，自杀了
Hmm. Shitloads.
嗯，很多
Would you ever think about it?
你想过没有？
Huh?
什么？
Would you ever think about killing yourself because you're a midget?
你有没有因为自己是侏儒而想自杀？
Fuck, man! What kind of question is that?
操，伙计！这算是什么问题？
We're just chatting, aren't we?
聊天而已，不是吗？
See, Ken, this is the kind of hotel Harry should have put us in.
看，肯，哈里应该给我们订这样的 旅馆才对
A five-star, with prostitutes in.
五星级，还有妓女
You know, sometimes, I think Harry doesn't even give a shit about us at all.
你知道，有时候 我想哈里压根就不在乎我们
Has he still not called?
他还没有来电话吗？
No. Still hasn't called.
没有，还没
No news is good news, eh?
没有消息就是好消息，对吧？
RAY: Hmm.
嗯
Who's she?
她是谁？
JIMMY: There's gonna be a war, man.
将会有场战争的，伙计
I can see it.
我能预见到
There's gonna be a war between the blacks and between the whites.
黑人和白人之间将会有一场战争
You ain't even gonna need a uniform no more.
甚至不用穿上军装
This ain't gonna be a war where you pick your side.
这场战争你没法选择你站在哪边
Your side's already picked for you.
你站在哪边早就命中注定了
And I know whose side I'm fighting on. I'm fighting with the blacks.
我知道我站在哪边 我和黑人一起战斗
The whites are gonna get their heads kicked in!
我们要把白人打的抱头鼠窜！
JIMMY: You don't decide this shit, man.
这不是你来决定的，伙计
Well, who are the half-castes gonna fight with?
喔，那些混血儿站在哪边呢？
The blacks, man. That's obvious.
黑人，伙计，很明显的嘛
But what about the Pakistanis?
巴基斯坦人呢？
The blacks. What about...
- 黑人 - 那…
Think of a hard one.
想个难的
What about the Vietnamese?
越南人呢？
The blacks!
黑人！
Well, I'm definitely fighting with the blacks if they've got the Vietnamese.
喔，如果黑人有越南人助阵的话 那我也加入
So, hang on.
等等
Would all of the white midgets in the world be fighting
世界上所有的白矮人都会和
against all the black midgets in the world?
黑矮人战斗喽？
Yeah.
是的
That would make a good film!
那要拍成电影一定是经典！
You don't know how much shit I've had to take off of black midgets, man.
你是不知道，我以前被黑矮人欺负的多惨
That's...
这个…
Undeniably true.
你不说我也知道
See, Jimmy,
看，吉米
my wife was black.
我妻子是黑人
And I loved her very much.
我很爱她
And in 1976, she was murdered by a white man.
1976年，她被一个白人杀害了
So, where the fuck am I supposed to stand in all this blood and carnage?
那么，我他妈的 在这血雨腥风中该站在哪边？
Did they get the guy who did it?
抓到那个凶手了吗？
A friend of mine got him.
我的一个朋友抓住了他
Harry Waters got him.
哈里·沃特斯抓到了
So tell me, Jim, whose side do I fight on in this wonderful war?
那告诉我，吉姆 我这场战争里该站在哪边？
I think you need to weigh up all your options
我想你需要权衡所有的因素
and let your conscience decide, Ken.
然后让你的良心去决定，肯
Two manky hookers and a racist dwarf.
两个肮脏的妓女和一个种族主义侏儒
I think I'm heading home.
我还是回家好了
Yeah. I think I'll come with you.
嗯，我和你一起走
What's... Back off, shorty!
走开，矮子
You don't know karate.
你可不会空手道
Don't say you didn't have it coming.
别说这不是你罪有应得！
Shortarse!
死矮子！
Meeting Yuri.
我找宥利
Yes, I'm Yuri.
嗯，我就是
Mr. Waters said that might be necessary.
沃特斯先生说可能用得上
There are a lot of alcoves in the Koningin Astrid Park.
阿斯特丽德公园有很多幽僻的地方
You use this word, "alcoves"?
你用“幽僻的地方”这个单词吧？
"Alcoves"? Yes. Sometimes.
“幽僻的地方”？用，有时候
There are not many people around in these alcoves in Christmastime.
圣诞节的时候那里人都很少
If I were to murder a man, I would murder him here.
如果我要杀人，我会在哪儿杀他
Are you sure this is the right word, "alcoves"?
你确定你没用错词，“幽僻的地方”？
"Alcoves," yes. It's kind of like "nooks and crannies."
“幽僻的地方”，嗯 和“隐蔽的地方”差不多的意思
"Nooks and crannies," yes. Perhaps this would be more accurate.
“隐蔽的地方”，嗯，也许这更确切一点
"Nooks and crannies," rather than "alcoves." Yeah.
“隐蔽的地方”比“幽僻的地方”更好，嗯
You are going to do it, aren't you? Mr. Waters will be very disappointed...
你会杀了他的，对吧？ 要不沃特斯先生会很失望…
Of course I'm going to fucking do it.
我他妈的当然会了
It's what I do.
这就是我的工作
Your friend was behaving rather oddly this morning.
你朋友今天可有点古怪
Oddly? How?
古怪？怎么了？
Well, he asked me about the baby, and if I wanted a boy or a girl.
喔，他问我怀孕的事 问我是想要男孩还是女孩
I said I didn't mind as long as it's healthy, of course.
当然，我说只要健健康康的 男女都无所谓了
But then he gave me 200 euros to give to the baby.
但是然后他就给我200欧元 说是给孩子的
I refused, obviously, but he was quite insistent.
我当然拒绝了，但是他一直坚持
Would you give it back to him when you see him?
你见到他请把钱还他好吗？
I don't want to appear ungrateful, but it seemed like all the money he had.
我不是不领情 只是看起来这是他身上所有的钱了
Do you know where he is now? He said he was going to the park.
- 你知道他去哪了吗？ - 他说他去公园走走
Sorry, Ray.
对不住了，雷
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
Ray, don't!
雷，不要！
Fucking hell! Where the fuck did you come from?
见鬼！你他妈从哪冒出来的？
I was behind the thing. What the fuck are you doing, Ray?
我刚才躲在那后面 你他妈的这是干什么呢，雷？
What the fuck are you doing?
你他妈又是想干什么？
Nothing.
没什么
Oh, my God!
哦，天哪
You were gonna kill me. No, I wasn't.
- 你要杀我 - 不，不是
You were gonna kill yourself!
你差点自杀了！
I'm allowed to.
我有这个权利啊
No, you're not!
不，你没有
What?
什么？
I'm not allowed to and you are? How's that fair?
我不能杀我，你却能杀我？ 这是哪门子道理？
Can we go somewhere and talk about this, please?
找个地方坐下来谈谈，好吧？
I wasn't gonna go through with it, Ray.
我下不了手，雷
You fucking looked like you were gonna go fucking through with it.
可你他妈的看起来就要得手了呢
Where'd you get that gun?
枪是哪里来的？
A friend of Harry's.
哈里的朋友的
Fuck, man.
靠，伙计
Let me see it.
我看看
Silencer, too.
还有消音器哈
Nice.
很好
Mine's a bloody girl's gun.
我的他妈的是女式手枪
I'm keeping it. Pardon me?
- 我来保管了 - 什么？
Give me me gun back. You're not getting it back.
- 把枪还我 - 不还
You're a suicide case.
你有自杀倾向
And you were trying to shoot me in the fucking head.
你他妈还想一枪把我崩了呢
You're not getting that gun back.
反正枪不会给你的
A great day this has turned out to be.
今天看来还真有趣了
I'm suicidal, me mate tries to kill me,
我想自杀，我的搭档想杀我
me gun gets nicked and we're still in fucking Bruges.
我的枪被没收了，我们他妈的还在布鲁日
Listen, I'm gonna give you some money and put you on a train somewhere.
听着，我给你点钱然后送你上火车
Back to England?
回英国？
You can't go back to England, Ray. You'd be a dead man!
你可不能会英国了，雷 回去你就死定了
(CRYING) I want to be a dead man.
我倒是真想死呢
Have you been missing something?
你是不是忘了这茬儿了？
You don't want to be a dead man, Ray.
你不会想死的，雷
I killed a little boy!
我杀死了一个小男孩
Then save the next little boy.
那下一次救一个小男孩
Just go away somewhere,
走吧
get out of this business and try to do something good.
别做这行当了，做些好事
You're not gonna help anybody dead.
人死不能复生
bring that boy back.
那个孩子已经回不来了
But you might save the next one.
但是下一次你也许能救谁
What am I gonna be, a doctor?
我要当什么，医生？
You need exams.
得考试呢
Do anything, Ray. Do anything.
做什么都行，雷，什么都行
RAY: What a wanker!
真贱！
He said this whole trip,
他说这次旅行
this whole being in Bruges thing,
来布鲁日旅行
was just to give you one last, joyful memory before you died.
都只是想在你死之前给你 一段美好的回忆
In Bruges?
在布鲁日？
The Bahamas, maybe.
去巴哈马还差不多！ （旅游胜地，人称“加勒比苏黎世”）
Why fucking Bruges?
为什么要到布鲁日来？
I suppose it's cheaper.
我想可能是更便宜吧
The rest of the acid and the ecstasy.
这是剩下的迷幻药和快乐丸
Can I have me gun back, please?
能把枪给我吗？
What am I gonna do, Ken?
我该做什么呢，肯？
What am I gonna do? Just keep moving.
- 我该做什么？ - 继续生活就行了
Keep on moving.
继续生活
Try not to think about it.
别想太多
Learn a new language, maybe?
或许学一门新的语言？
Sure, I can hardly do English.
我是太依赖英语了
That's one thing I like about Europe, though.
不过这是我喜欢欧洲的一个原因
You don't have to learn any of their languages.
你不用学他们的语言
Just forget about home for a while.
暂时忘记一些事情吧
See how the land lies in six years, seven years.
六七年之后再看形势怎么样
Seven years is not that long.
七年也没想象中久
It's longer than that boy got.
那小男孩七岁都没有呢
Me first fucking job.
我第一次杀人任务呢
Great hitman I turned out to be.
看来我是个超级职业杀手呢
Some people just aren't cut out for it, Ray.
有些人不是干这行的料，雷
Are you?
你是吗？
When are you going back to England?
你什么时候回英国？
I'll head back in a couple of hours or something.
我过几个小时就回
Harry's not gonna be mad at you, is he? For letting me go?
哈里会对你大发雷霆的，对吧？ 你都把我放了
I'll sort out Harry.
我会揍他的
Just tell him I'll have probably killed meself in a fortnight, anyway.
你告诉他也许 我两周内就自杀了也不一定
You won't, will you, Ray?
你不会的，是吧，雷？
Harry? It's Ken.
哈里？我是肯
Listen to this noise.
听这声音
Do you know what that is?
知道是什么吗？
Yeah, I know you know it's a train. Do you know what train?
嗯，我知道你知道那是火车声 你知道是什么火车吗？
Well, it's a train that Ray just got on, and he's alive and he's well,
喔，那是雷刚上的那趟火车 他活着，好好的
and he doesn't know where he's going and neither do I.
他不知道火车去哪 我也不知道
So if you need to do your worst, do your worst.
你爱怎么的怎么的吧，我奉陪到底
You've got the address of the hotel. I'll be here waiting.
你已经知道旅馆的地址了 我在那恭候大驾
Because I've got to quite like Bruges, now.
我现在非常喜欢布鲁日
It's like a fucking fairytale or something.
这里他妈的简直就像是仙境呢
Harry.
哈里
Harry!
哈里！
What?
怎么？
It's an inanimate fucking object.
那他妈只是没有生命的东西！
You're an inanimate fucking object!
你他妈只是没有生命的东西！
Now, you lot be good for your mummy and lmamoto, okay?
你们乖乖的听妈妈和今本小姐的话
'Cause Daddy's got to go away for a few days.
爸爸要出去几天
Where are you going?
你去哪？
I've got to go to Bruges.
布鲁日
Bruges? Where's that?
布鲁日？在哪？
It's in Belgium.
比利时
Why would anybody have to go to Belgium?
干嘛要去比利时呢？
'Cause I've got to sort something out.
我有些事情得处理
Is it something to do with the phone?
和刚才的电话有关吗？
It's something to do with Ken.
和肯有关
It's a matter of honor.
事关荣誉
Well, it ain't gonna be dangerous, is it?
喔，那会很危险了，是吧？
Well, of course it's gonna be dangerous if it's a matter of fucking honor!
事关荣誉他妈的当然会很危险了！
You are bringing the fellas with you?
你带伙计过去吗？
Tell me you're bringing the fellas with you.
告诉我说你会带伙计过去！
Harry.
哈里
I'm sorry for calling you an inanimate object.
我很抱歉骂你没生命的东西
I was upset.
我当时太沮丧了
You're Irish? Yes.
- 你是爱尔兰人？ - 是的
What is your name?
你叫什么？
Derek Perlurrl.
德里克，佩，呃，鲁尔
You hit the Canadian.
你打了加拿大人
L"heet" the Canadian? I don't know what you're talking about.
我“热烈的”加拿大人？ 你说什么呢？
That's him! That's the motherfucker.
就是他，就是那个混蛋
You hit the Canadian, yeah?
你打了加拿大人，是吧？
Canadian? Shit.
加拿大人？靠
We're taking you back to Bruges. Brilliant.
- 我们把你带回布鲁日 - 好极了
Aye aye.
船长好啊
YURl: Take your pick, Mr. Waters.
自己挑吧，沃特斯先生
(CHUCKLES) An Uzi?
乌兹拉冲锋枪？
I'm not from South Central Los fucking Angeles.
我他妈可不是洛杉矶南部中心来的
I didn't come here to shoot 20 black 10-year-olds in a fucking drive-by.
我可不是要他妈开着车 射杀20个10岁大的黑人小孩
I want a normal gun for a normal person.
我要杀一个普通人 所以只要一把普通的枪
I knew he wouldn't kill the guy.
我知道他不会杀那个人的
I could see it in his eyes when I was telling him about the alcoves.
但我和他说“幽僻的地方”的时候我能 从他的眼睛里看出来
About the what? The alcoves.
- 说什么？ - 幽僻的地方
The alcoves in the Koningin Astrid Park.
阿斯特丽德公园里幽僻的地方
Oh, I also have some dumdums.
我还有些达姆弹 （杀伤力、撕裂能力极大的违禁子弹）
You use this word, "dumdums"? The bullets that make the head explode?
你说“达姆弹”吗？ 那种能把人头打爆的子弹？
Dumdums, yeah.
达姆弹，嗯
Would you like some of these dumdums?
想要一些吗？
I know I shouldn't,
我知道我不应该要的
but I will.
不过我还是要了
Motherfucker.
他妈个逼的
Is he talking to me?
他是在和我说话吗？
No, Eirik's on your side, Mr. Waters.
不，埃里克可是和你一边的，沃特斯先生
Your young friend blinded him last night.
你的小弟昨晚把他弄瞎了
Ray did?
雷干的？
I was trying to rob him and he took my gun from me.
我想抢劫他，他把我的枪抢走了
And the gun was full of blanks,
那枪里都是空弹
and he shot the blank into my eye.
他就对着我开空枪
And now, I cannot see from this eye ever again, the doctors say.
现在好了 医生说我这只眼睛再也看不见了
Well, to be honest, it sounds like it was all your fault.
喔，说实话 听起来你是自作自受呢
What?
什么？
I mean, basically, if you're robbing a man and you're only carrying blanks,
我是说，如果你要抢人枪却空弹
and you allow your gun to be taken off you,
枪还被抢走了
and you allow yourself to be shot in the eye with a blank,
你还让他对着你的眼睛开空枪
for which I assume the person has to get quite close to you, then,
我想他离你很近吧
yeah, really, it's all your fault for being such a poof.
所以只能说你太妇人之仁，自作自受
So why don't you stop whingeing and cheer the fuck up?
你他妈还是别叽叽歪歪发牢骚了 打起精神来吧
YURl: Eirik, I really wouldn't respond.
埃里克，要是我可不会理他
I thought you wanted the guy dead?
你不是想杀了那家伙吗？
I do want the guy dead. I want him fucking crucified.
我的确也想杀了他 我想把他五马分尸，千刀万剐
But it don't change the fact that he stitched you up like a blind, little gay boy.
但是那都无法改变他把你弄成瞎子 这个事实，小娘们
Does it?
是吧？
Thanks for the gun, Yuri.
谢谢你的枪了，宥利
Well?
然后？
The boy is suicidal, Harry.
他想自杀呢，哈里
He's a walking dead man.
他只是行尸走肉罢了
Keeps going on about Hell and purgatory...
不断的在地狱和炼狱之间游走
When I phoned you yesterday, did I ask you,
昨天我打电话的时候，我有没有和你说
"Ken, will you do me a favor and become Ray's psychiatrist, please?"
“肯，能帮我劝劝雷吗？”
No. What I think I asked you was, " Could you go blow his fucking head off for me?"
没有！ 我是和你说“你他妈能帮我宰了他吗？”
"He's suicidal"?
“他要自杀？”
I'm suicidal. You're suicidal. Everybody's fucking suicidal!
我还要自杀呢！你也自杀得了！ 大家都他妈自杀得了！
We don't all keep going on about it!
可有谁真自杀了！
Has he killed himself yet? No. So he's not fucking suicidal, is he?
他杀死自己了吗？没有 所以他他妈没自杀，对吧？
He put a loaded gun to his head this morning. I stopped him.
他把装弹的枪顶着自己的头 我阻止了他
He... What? This gets fucking worse!
他…什么？他妈越来越不像话了！
We were down in the park...
我们在公园里…
Let me get this right. You were down in the park?
等等，你们去公园了？
What's that got to do with fucking anything?
去公园干屁？
Let me get this right. Not only have you refused to kill the boy,
我没弄错的话，你不但不杀他
you've even stopped the boy from killing himself,
还阻止他自杀
which would have solved my problem,
杀了他就能解决我的难题了
solved your problem,
也能解决你的
which sounds like it would've solved the boy's problem.
听起来也能让他解脱
It wouldn't have solved his problem.
那不会让他解脱的
Ken, if I had killed a little kid, accidentally or otherwise,
肯，如果我杀死了一个小孩 不管是意外还是怎么的
I wouldn't have thought twice.
我一点都不会犹豫
I'd have killed myself on the fucking spot. On the fucking spot.
我立马就自杀，立马他妈自杀！
I'd have stuck the gun in me mouth on the fucking spot!
我会立马把枪塞进嘴里
That's you, Harry. The boy has the capacity to change.
那是你，哈里，那个孩子还有机会
The boy has the capacity to do something decent with his life.
他还有能力和机会做些好事
Excuse me, Ken. I have the capacity to change.
抱歉，肯，我才有机会
Yeah, you do. You've the capacity to get fucking worse!
嗯，你有，你只有让事情他妈变坏的能力
Yeah, now I'm getting down to it!
嗯，现在我明白了
Harry, let's face it.
哈里，我们还是面对现实吧
And I'm not being funny, I mean no disrespect,
我不是开玩笑，也不是对你不敬
but you're a cunt.
但是你是个混蛋！
You're a cunt now, you've always been a cunt.
你现在是个混蛋，你一直都是！
And the only thing that's gonna change is you're gonna become an even bigger cunt.
唯一会改变的事情就是 你会变得越来越混蛋
Maybe have some more cunt kids.
也许还会有更多的混蛋孩子
Leave my kids fucking out of it. What have they done?
别他妈把我的孩子扯进来 他们难道做了什么坏事？
You fucking retract that bit about my cunt fucking kids!
你他妈的赶紧 收回关于我混蛋孩子的那句话！
I retract that bit about your cunt fucking kids.
我收回关于你混蛋孩子的那句话！
Insulting my fucking kids! That's going overboard, mate!
敢侮辱我的孩子！ 你这就太过份了，伙计！
I retracted it, didn't I?
我不是收回了，是吧？
Still leaves you being a cunt.
不过你他妈的依然是个混蛋
Yeah, I fucking got that.
嗯，我他妈知道
Where's Ray now?
雷现在在哪？
Oh, right about now, Ray is in one or other
哦，现在啊
of the one million towns in mainland Europe it's possible to be in, other than here.
雷可能在成千上万个欧洲大陆城市的 任何一个里，反正不在这
I'll get all the money back to you soon as I get through to me friend.
我找到我朋友之后一定把钱都还你
It's not a problem, Raymond.
没事的，雷蒙
And I'll get all your acid and your ecstasy back to you, too.
还有把迷幻药和快乐丸也都还你
English humor!
英式幽默！
I'm assuming you've got your gun on you.
我想你身上带着枪吧？
That Yuri bloke's a funny fella, isn't he?
那个叫宥利的是个有趣的小子，是吧？
He does yoga.
他练瑜伽
"The alcoves."
“幽僻的地方”
Was he going on to you about the alcoves?
他和你说幽僻的地方了？
"The alcoves in the Koningin Astrid Park."
阿斯特丽德公园里幽僻的地方
Harry, I know you gotta do what you gotta do.
哈里，我知道你得做你该做的事
It's a bit crowded round here, you know?
这里人太多了，是吧？
Well, I'm not gonna have a shootout
喔，我可没打算
in the middle of a thousand fucking Belgians, am I?
在他妈一群比利时人当中开枪
Not to mention the other nationalities, just on their holidays.
别说还有好多别的国家来度假的人
Hmm.
嗯
To see the swans and the Gothic and all the fairytale stuff, eh?
来看天鹅和教堂还有仙境什么的？
Are you trying to fucking wind me up? No, Harry.
- 你是他妈想激怒我是吗？ - 不，哈里
On top of calling me a cunt and calling me kids cunts.
叫我混蛋也就算了 还说我的孩子也是混蛋
I might just have to fucking shoot you right here.
真他妈该在这把你毙了
Christ!
天！
Let's go up the bell tower.
我们到钟楼楼顶去吧
Be quiet up there this time of evening.
晚上的这个时候那里应该没人了
Let's go up there.
我们上去吧
Yeah. Canadians.
嗯，加拿大人
I feel a bit bad. They didn't kill John Lennon, did they?
我有点内疚了 不是他们杀死的约翰·列侬 ，是吧？
Anyway, supposed to turn up to court here in two days.
不管怎么样了 两天后就得去对簿公堂了
Are you going to turn up?
你会去吗？
Don't know.
不知道
What have I got to stay for really?
我为什么要驻足停留呢？
The most beautiful woman
这有在你灰暗的人生中
you've ever seen
你所见过的
in all of your stupid life.
最漂亮的女人
The tower is closed this evening.
钟楼晚上不开
No way. It's supposed to be open till 7:00.
不是吧，开到七点的啊
The tower is usually open until 7:00.
以前是到七点
Yesterday an American had a heart attack up the tower.
昨天有个美国人在上面心脏病突发
Today the tower is closed.
所以今天关的早
Here, cranky, here's 100 for you. We're only gonna be 20 minutes.
来，小子，给你100 我们就上去20分钟
The tower is closed this evening.
今天！晚上！钟楼！不开！
Understand, Englishman?
明白了，英国佬？
Jimmy, I've been wanting to say
吉米，我一直想说
I'm really sorry for karate-chopping you the other night.
很抱歉那天用空手道打了你
That was way out of order.
那实在是太过份了
You know, Ray, I'd find it easier to believe and forgive you, somehow,
你知道的，雷，如果你们两个
if the two of you weren't laughing straight in my fucking face!
我会更乐意原谅你的 如果他妈别当着我的面偷笑
It's for the goddamn movie, man.
这样都是为了那部狗屁电影
It is a nice town, Harry.
这是个很好的地方，哈里
I'm glad I got to see it.
我很高兴我来过这
I didn't mean to be taking the piss out of it being a fairytale place.
我不是虚与委蛇的说 这是个神话般的地方
It is a fairytale place.
这就是个神话般的地方
It really is. Hmm.
- 真的是 - 嗯
It's just a shame it's in Belgium, really.
只是可惜是在比利时
But then you figure if it wasn't in Belgium, if it was somewhere good,
但是你也知道如果不是在比利时 而是在其他著名的地方的话
there'd be too many people coming to see it. It would spoil the whole thing.
就会有太多的人来这 这样就会毁了它的
Well, I'm glad I got to see it
喔，我很高兴来过这
before I died.
在我死之前
What are you doing?
你这是干什么？
What are you fucking doing?
你他妈的这是干什么？
I'm not fighting anymore, Harry.
我不会再抵抗了，哈里
All right, then I'm blowing your fucking head off.
那好，那我就一枪把你崩了
Don't come over all Gandhi. What are you fucking doing?
别学什么甘地了，你这算哪门子事？
Ken, stop messing about, please.
肯，别磨叽了，好吧
Pick up your gun. I know I'm going to beat you anyway
拿起枪，不管怎么样我都会杀你的
'Cause you're a spaz, but... Harry,
- 你是个笨蛋，不过… - 哈里
I'm totally in your debt.
我欠你的
The things that have gone between us in the past,
我们之间的情谊
I love you unreservedly for all that.
因为所有的那些我无条件的爱你
What?
什么？
For your integrity.
你的正直
For your honor.
你的荣耀
I love you.
我爱你
The boy had to be let go.
你应该放过他
The boy had to be given a chance.
你应该给他一个机会
And if to do that, I had to say, " Fuck you, and fuck what I owe you,
如果你执意要杀他，那我只能说 “去你妈的，去他妈我欠你的
"and fuck everything that's gone on between us," then that's what I had to do.
去他们我们之间的情谊” 我只能这么做
But I'm not fighting you.
但是我不会和你争斗
And I accept, totally, everything you've got to do.
我接受，全部接受你的惩罚
I accept it. Totally.
我接受，全部接受
Oh, yeah?
哦，是吗？
Yeah.
嗯
Well, you say all that fucking stuff, I can't fucking shoot you now, can I?
喔，你说了那么多，我他妈的就不能开枪了，是吧？
It's entirely up to you, Harry.
那是你的自由，哈里
It's entirely your call.
那看你自己的选择
All I'm saying is I'm not fighting.
只是我，绝对不会反抗
Oh, you fucking cunt!
哦，他妈的你这个王八蛋！
Look, I'm not gonna do nothing to you
听着，我不可能因为你他妈像
just 'Cause you're standing about like Robert fucking Powell.
罗伯特·波威尔一样大义凛然 我操就不会为难你
Like who? Like Robert fucking Powell
- 像谁？ - 像他妈 罗伯特·波威尔
out of Jesus of fucking Nazareth!
《拿撒勒的耶稣》饰演耶稣的那个
My fucking leg!
我的腿
The psycho dwarf turns out to just be a loveable little schoolboy,
最后发现那个患精神病的矮子 只是一个可爱的小学生
and it's all some kind of Boschian nightmare.
所有的一切只是噩梦而已
Kiss my ass!
真他妈无聊！
I guess at least there weren't any black people involved, eh, Jimmy?
我猜里面没有黑人吧，呃，吉米？
I wasn't...
我不是..
I wasn't talking about...
我不是在说…
There's gonna be a war between all the blacks and all the whites.
所有的黑人和白人将会有一场战争的
And all the black midgets and all the white midgets,
所有的黑矮人和白矮人也会有
which would actually be really good.
这样可棒极了
That's just cocaine.
我那时不是嗑了可卡因嘛
He didn't even want the Vietnamese on his side!
他甚至不想要越南人在他这一边
That's just cocaine.
我那时嗑了可卡因而已
Listen, we're filming down by the pointy building tonight.
听着，我们今晚在那个尖尖的建筑那拍
It might actually be good for once.
可能会很好玩哦
You guys should come along.
你们一起去吧
We... I think we're just gonna have a quiet one tonight, Jimmy.
我们…我想我们今晚需要一个安静点的地方，吉米
That's how it is!
我明白了！
In another life.
不同的世界啊！
They're great, aren't they?
他们是好人，对吧？
You didn't. You didn't!
你没有！你没有！
Mr. Waters? Mr. Waters?
沃特斯先生？沃特斯先生？
Who's that? It's Eirik.
- 谁？ - 埃里克
The blind boy? Yeah.
- 那个瞎子？ - 嗯
Yes.
嗯
What do you fucking want?
他妈你想干嘛？
The guy you're looking for,
你要找的那个人
the guy Ray, he's downstairs at the bar.
那个雷，他在楼下的酒吧里
I'm sorry, Ken.
很抱歉，肯
But you can't kill a kid and expect to get away with it.
但是你不可能杀死一个小孩 却能逍遥法外
You just can't.
不可能
Where? To the left when you come out.
- 在哪？ - 出去之后左走
The bar to the left.
酒吧的左边
Ken!
肯！
Ken! Ken!
肯！肯！
Harry's here.
哈里来了
What?
什么？
Take
拿着
my gun.
我的枪
Ken?
肯？
Where's my gun?
我的枪在哪？
I'm gonna die now, I think.
我快要死了吧，我想
Oh, Ken!
哦，肯！
Jesus!
天哪！
Mr. Blakely said you had left.
布莱克里先生说你已经走了啊
I need the key to the room right now.
我要房间的钥匙，快点
Quickly, now!
快点！
And you gotta go home right now. It's very, very dangerous here.
你现在赶紧回家去 这里非常非常危险
All right? Go home! Right now! Okay.
- 好吧？回家去！快点！ - 好的
MARIE: No, I won't let you up there! Put that gun away, right now!
不，我不会让你上去的！ 把枪放下，快点！
HARRY: Lady, get out of my fucking way, please.
女士，请你他妈让开！
No, I won't. I won't get out of your way.
不，我不让
You'll have to go through me.
要过去先杀了我吧
Well, obviously, I'm not gonna through you, am I, with a baby and that?
喔，很明显，我不会杀你 你怀孕了，不是吗？
I'm a nice person.
我是个好人
But could you just get out of the fucking way, please?
但是他妈的请你让开好吧？
Marie!
玛丽！
Just let him come up, it's okay.
让他上来吧，没事的
Harry, swear not to start shooting until she's left the hotel.
哈里，答应我她离开了这 我们再开打
I swear not to start shooting till she's left the hotel. I totally swear.
我发誓她走了我才会开枪 我郑重的发誓
Well, I'm not going anywhere.
喔，我哪都不去
This is my hotel.
这是我的旅馆
So you can fuck off!
你他妈给我滚！
I suppose you've got a gun up there? Yeah.
- 你拿到枪了吧？ - 嗯
Then what are we gonna do? We can't stand here all night.
那你准备怎么办？ 我们不可能这样站一晚上吧
Why don't you both put your guns down and go home?
你们两位干嘛不一起把枪放下 然后回家去？
Don't be stupid. This is the shootout.
别傻了，这是枪战
Harry, I've got an idea. What?
- 哈里，我有个主意 - 什么？
My room faces onto the canal, right?
我的房间下面是条运河，是吧？
I'm gonna go back to me room, jump into the canal,
我回我的房间，跳进运河
see if I can swim to the other side and escape.
看我能不能游到对面然后逃走
Right. If you go outside and round the corner,
- 好 - 你可以出去在那个角上
you can shoot at me from there and try and get me.
朝我开枪，看能不能杀了我
That way, we leave this lady and her baby out of the whole, entire thing.
这样，我们就不会把那位女士 和她的孩子牵扯进来了
Do you completely promise to jump into the canal?
你发誓一定跳进运河？
I don't want to run out there, come back in 10 minutes
我看不想跑出去，10分钟之后回来
and find you fucking hiding in a cupboard.
却发现你躲在壁橱里
I completely promise, Harry.
我发誓，哈里
I'm not gonna risk having another little kid die, am I?
我可不想再让一个小孩死了，对吧？
So, hang on, I go outside, then I go which way, right or left?
等等，我出去，然后往哪边走？ 右还是左？
You go right, don't you?
右，对吧？
You can see it from the doorway! It's a big fucking canal!
你从门口就能看见了！ 他妈的那么大一运河
All right. Jesus! I've only just got here, haven't I?
好的，天！我刚从那过来的，是吧？
Okay. On a count of "one, two, three, go," okay?
好的，数“1，2，3”，好吧？
Okay.
好
What? Who says it?
谁来数？
Oh, you say it.
哦，你数吧
You guys are crazy.
你们两个都疯了
Are you ready? Ready.
- 好了吗？ - 好了
Set? Set.
- 预备？ - 预备
One, two, three, go!
1，2，3，开始！
Keep driving!
接着开！
No way. You're way too far away.
不可能，你离我太远了
The little boy.
那个小孩
That's right, Ray.
对，雷
Oh.
哦
I see.
我明白了
No, Harry.
不，哈里
He's not...
他不是…
You've got to stick to your principles.
你得遵守规则不是
RAY. ; There's a Christmas tree somewhere in London
在伦敦，有一棵圣诞树
with a bunch of presents underneath it that'll never be opened.
下面有好多礼物 却永远没人去打开它们了
And I thought, "If I survive all this, I'll go to that house,
我就想“如果我能活下去 我会到他家去
"apologize to the mother there,
向他母亲道歉
"and accept whatever punishment she chose for me."
然后接受惩罚，不管那是什么
Prison, death, it didn't matter.
坐牢，枪毙，都无所谓了
Because at least in prison and at least in death, you know,
因为不管是坐牢还是枪毙，你知道
I wouldn't be in fucking Bruges.
他妈我都不会在布鲁日了”
But then, like a flash, it came to me, and I realized,
忽然之间，我又意识到
"Fuck, man, maybe that's what Hell is.
操阿，也许这就是地狱
"The entire rest of eternity spent in fucking Bruges!"
我剩下的日子都得他妈 在布鲁日呆着了
And I really, really hoped I wouldn't die.
我真的，真的很希望我不会死
I really, really
我真的，真的很希望我能活着